# **Daniel J. Marchetto**

(412) 720-3173 daniel.marchetto@gatech.edu

Google Scholar daniel-marchetto.github.io GitHub: daniel-marchetto LinkedIn: daniel-marchetto

Behavioral and Data Scientist. My current project involves utilizing my skills to learn the experience and motivations of graduate students on the r/GradSchool subreddit forum. This project includes topic modeling, sentiment analysis, and online surveying.

#### **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy in Public Policy, Georgia Institute of Technology Specialization: Science and Technology Policy	Expected 2022
Master of Science in Computational Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology	Expected 2022
Master of Science in Statistics, Georgia Institute of Technology	2021
Master of Public Policy, Arizona State University	2018
Bachelor of Science in Psychology, Carnegie Mellon University	2016

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Topic Classification of Electric Vehicle Consumer Experience with Transformer-based Deep Learning, Patterns 2021 Ha, S., Marchetto, D.J., Dharur, S., Asensio, O.I.

Extracting User Behavior at Electric Vehicle Charging Stations with Transformer Deep Learning Models, CARMA 2020 Marchetto, D.J., Ha, S., Dharur, S., Asensio, O.I.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

**Graduate Research Assistant** August 2018 — May 2021

Dr. Julia Melkers

- Georgia Tech Analyzed themes from phone interviews with CS graduate students to learn sources of self-efficacy.
- Designed the structure and elements of a large-scale survey including the development of a novel self-efficacy scale.
- Collected and analyzed literature relating to faculty career development and online education.

Dr. Omar Isaac Asensio Georgia Tech

- Designed and implemented survey to crowd-source partial training labels for use in BERT and XLNET topic classification task.
- Analyzed correlates of consumer dissatisfaction extracted from unstructured reviews using fixed-effect models in R.
- Analyzed effects of HUD funding on electricity consumption in Albany, GA with matching and difference-in-difference models.

#### **Smart Community Corps Fellow**

Institute for People and Technology

Georgia Tech

- Graduate Fellow in project to improve data connectivity and transparency in the City of Albany, GA.
- Designed geohub website using ESRI's web service to ease access to public city data.
- · Consulted on design of SQL database for linkage of city records relating to economic development and utility consumption.

## **Graduate Research Assistant**

January 2017 - July 2018

May 2019 — September 2019

Dr. Lily Hsueh

Arizona State

- Conducted literature search on firm-level carbon emission reduction and its relation to corporate self-governance.
- Collected firm-level emission data and Twitter data from S&P 500 corporations using Thomson Reuters and Python.
- Analyzed trends between Twitter postings and corporate emissions using classification and regression techniques in R.

**Research Intern** June 2017 — August 2017 Republic Services Phoenix, AZ

• Managed project to analyze sources of turnover in material recycling facilities.

Conducted phone and on-site interviews with key stakeholders and presented results to members of upper management.

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

Co-Instructor	Research Design in Policy Science	Spring 2022
<b>Graduate Teaching Assistant</b>	Engineering Ethics	Fall 2021
	Big Data and Public Policy	Spring 2020
	Economics and Public Policy	Fall 2017, Spring 2018

### SKILLS

Tools and Languages	R, Python, Julia, SQL, Git, धर्EX
Analytic Techniques	Regression, Classification, Clustering, Structural Equation Modeling, Multilevel Modeling,
	Experimental Design, Survey Design, Psychometrics, Text Analysis